(Stop!)
((Deja de correr).)
(Stop running.)
(Deja de correr.)
(Hunt her down.)
(Cazarla.)
(Stop!)
(¡Alto!)
- Stop! - Stop running.
- ¡Alto! - Deja de correr.
- Don't let her get away.
- No la dejes huir.
Hunt her down.
Cazarla.
Stop!
Detente!
Stop! Come on.
Detente, vamos.
(Nie Sangyu)
(Nie Sangyu)
Nie Sangyu.
Sra. Sangyu.
(Ning Yuxuan)
(Ning Yuxuan)
Miss Wen's life is uncertain.
La vida de la señorita Wen es incierta.
Go back with me.
Vuelve conmigo.
I didn't kill her!
¡No la maté!
I told you!
¡Te lo dije!
Ning Yuxuan.
Ning Yuxuan.
We've been married for four years.
Hemos estado casados durante cuatro años.
Why are you pushing me so hard?
¿Por qué me empujas tan fuerte?
I will say it one last time.
Lo diré una última vez.
Go back.
Vuelve.
Lovebirds got separated.
Lovebirds se separaron.
The mirror was broken.
Se rompió el espejo.
A couple left each other.
Una pareja se dejó.
My husband.
Mi marido.
I curse you for
Te maldigo por
a lifetime of despair
una vida de desesperación
and pain
y dolor
like mine,
como el mío,
with a tragic end.
con un trágico final.
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
What are you going to do?
¿Qué vas a hacer?
Nie Sangyu!
¡Nie Sangyu!
(My hair just covered my forehead,)
(Mi pelo cubría mi frente,)
(and I folded flowers in front of the door.)
(y doblamos flores frente a la puerta.)
(You came here on horseback,)
(Viniste aquí a caballo,)
(while I was playing with green plum blossoms.)
(Mientras estaba jugando con flores de ciruelo verde.)
(When I married you at 14 years old,)
(Cuando me casé contigo a los 14 años,)
(I was too shy to smile.)
(Era demasiado tímida para sonreir.)
(I only stretched my eyebrows at the age of 15,)
(Solo extendía mis cejas a la edad de 15 años,)
(willing to be with you forever.)
(dispuestos a estar contigo para siempre.)
(When I was 16,)
(Cuando tenía 16 años,)
(you left home on a long journey to Yanyudui in Qutang Gorge.)
(Dejaste casa en un largo viaje a Yanyudui en la garganta de Qutang.)
=Romance of a Twin Flower=
= Romance de una flor gemela =
=Episode 1=
= Episodio 1 =
(Ning's Mansion)
(Mansión Ning)
(Madam, you woke up.)
(Señora, me despertó.)
Great.
Genial.
Yes, take the medicine.
Sí, toma la medicina.
Miss, who are you?
Señorita, ¿quién es?
Muxu.
Muxu.
Muxu?
¿Muxu?
I am your personal maid,
Soy tu dama personal,
(Muxu) Muxu, Your Ladyship.
(Muxu) Muxu, tu señoría.
Your Ladyship?
¿Su señoría?
Yes.
Sí.
You are the First Lady
Eres la Primera Dama
of Marquis Moyu's Mansion.
de la mansión del marqués Moyu.
Your Ladyship.
Señora.
Don't you like
¿No te gusta
my name?
mi nombre?
Your Ladyship, don't get angry.
Su señoría, no te enfades.
If you don't like it,
Si no te gusta,
just change my name.
solo cambia mi nombre.
Celery, Leek, and the like.
Apio, Leek y similares.
Everything will do.
Todo va a funcionar.
Don't get angry.
No te enfades.
Wait, Miss.
Espera, señorita.
Don't get angry, Your Ladyship.
No te enfades, señora.
- Don't do this. Get up. - Don't get angry.
- No hagas esto. Levántate. - No te enfades.
Get up. Come on.
Levántate. Vamos.
Well, the Marquis's Mansion
Bueno, la mansión del Marqués
and the First Lady you said
y a la Primera Dama le dijiste
have nothing to do with me.
no tienes nada que ver conmigo.
Did you make a mistake?
¿Has cometido un error?
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
You seem to be different.
Parece que eres diferente.
Could it be that you broke your brain
¿Podría ser que te rompiste el cerebro
when you fell off the cliff?
cuando se cayó del precipicio?
Fell off the cliff?
¿Se cayó del precipicio?
Who fell off the cliff?
¿Quién cayó del precipicio?
So crazy.
Tan loco.
Miss.
Señorita.
You seem to be occupied.
Parece que estás ocupada.
I am also busy.
También estoy ocupado.
I have to go.
Tengo que ir.
You can't get out.
No puedes salir.
There are so many people guarding outside.
Hay tanta gente custodiando fuera.
Why?
¿Por qué?
That's because you did...
Eso es porque lo hiciste...
You did something wrong.
Hiciste algo mal.
That's why you are locked up.
Es por eso que estás encerrado.
Marquis has ordered
Marqués ha ordenado
no one to come or go.
nadie va o viene.
I'll just leave for a while.
Me iré por un tiempo.
Okay.
Está bien.
I'm not leaving.
No me voy.
Be nice.
Sé amable.
I'm not going out.
No voy a salir.
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
Look.
Mira.
We need to think long term
Tenemos que pensar a largo plazo
about this matter.
sobre este asunto.
I fell off a cliff.
Me caí de un precipicio.
Then here I am.
Luego aquí estoy.
Yes.
Sí.
Then why did I fall off the cliff?
Entonces, ¿por qué caí del precipicio?
What happened
Qué pasó
before this?
antes de esto?
I dare not say.
No me atrevo a decir.
Why not?
¿Por qué no?
You asked me to say it.
Me pediste decirlo.
Say it.
Dilo.
It all started
Todo empezó
with a chicken.
con un pollo.
A chicken?
¿Un pollo?
(You came here on horseback,)
(Viniste aquí a caballo,)
(while I was playing with green plum blossoms.)
(Mientras estaba jugando con flores de ciruelo verde.)
(Ning's Mansion, Capital) (When I married you at 14 years old,)
(Ning 's Mansion, Capital) (Cuando me casé contigo a los 14 años,)
(I was too shy to smile.)
(Era demasiado tímida para sonreir.)
Get out of the way.
Fuera del camino.
(Banxia) Mr. Liu. Mr. Liu.
(Banxia) Sr. Liu.
Why are you back so late?
¿Por qué vuelves tan tarde?
Her Ladyship is waiting anxiously.
Su señoría está esperando con ansiedad.
Okay.
Está bien.
Take it in now.
Tómalo ahora.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Discúlpeme.
I don't know
No sé
what Her Ladyship is up to.
qué es su señoría
What did I want a chicken for?
¿Para qué quería un pollo?
Your name is Nie Sangyu,
Tu nombre es Nie Sangyu,
the eldest daughter of
la hija mayor de
General Zhenyuan Nie Xiangyuan.
general Zhenyuan Nie Xiangyuan.
You fell in love with Marquis Moyu Ning Yuxuan at first sight
Te enamoraste de Marquis Moyu ning Yuxuan a primera vista
and insisted on marrying him.
e insistió en casarse con él.
And
Y
you have a sobriquet.
tienes un sobrenombre.
No.1 She-devil of the Capital.
No.1 Diablo de la Capital.
She-devil?
¿Diablo?
Coming.
Viniendo.
Take it out and show me.
Llévalo y enséñame.
Yes, Your Ladyship.
Sí, su señoría.
Come out.
Sal.
Come...
Ven...
You!
¡Tú!
How dare you!
¡Cómo te atreves!
If you hurt the chicken,
Si lastimas al pollo,
you can't pay for your life.
no puedes pagar por tu vida.
It's all my fault.
Es toda mi culpa.
Your Ladyship, please show me mercy.
Su señoría, por favor muéstrame misericordia.
Okay.
Está bien.
Someone.
Alguien.
Reward Banxia
Recompensa a Banxia
with my plum blossom picture
con mi foto de flor de ciruelo
as a flower seal.
como un sello de flores.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Your Ladyship, please spare me!
Su señoría, ¡por favor, perdóname!
Your Ladyship!
¡Su señoría!
(Your Ladyship!)
(¡Su señoría!)
(Your Ladyship, please spare me!)
(¡Su señoría, por favor, perdónenme!)
(Marquis, Miss Xue!)
(Marquis, señorita Xue!)
(Save me!)
(¡Salve a mí!)
(Your Ladyship, please spare me!)
(¡Su señoría, por favor, perdónenme!)
(Marquis, Miss Xue!)
(Marquis, señorita Xue!)
Where is the Marquis?
¿Dónde está el Marqués?
(Save me!)
(¡Salve a mí!)
Is the bird's nest
Es el nido del pájaro
in the kitchen still warm?
en la cocina todavía caliente?
(Miss Xue!)
(¡Señorita Xue!)
I'm asking you.
Te lo pregunto.
Your Ladyship, no worries.
Su señoría, no te preocupes.
Marquis has gone to the Politics Hall,
Marqués ha ido a la Sala de Política,
and may not be back until later.
y puede que no vuelva hasta después.
You can have a meal first.
Puedes comer primero.
No.
No.
(Save me!)
(¡Sálvame!)
I'm going to wait for him to come back.
Voy a esperar a que regrese.
So horrible.
Tan horrible.
No, let's not talk about this.
No, No hablemos de esto.
Something else.
Otra cosa.
Tell me about my husband.
Dime sobre mi marido.
What kind of person is he?
¿Qué tipo de persona es?
Marquis devotes himself to government affairs
Marqués se dedica a los asuntos de gobierno
and spends most of his time in the Politics Hall.
y pasa la mayor parte de su tiempo en el Salón de la Política.
Moreover,
Además,
he achieves success when young,
alcanza el éxito cuando es joven,
and is the Left Consul of the present dynasty.
y es el cónsul de la izquierda de la dinastía actual.
He's also No. 1 Handsome Man of the Capital.
También es el hombre guapo número 1 de la Capital.
(Central Secretariat)
(Secretaría Central)
(Politics Hall)
(Salón de la Política)
Sir.
Señor.
This is the relevant document
Este es el documento pertinente
compiled on the case of
compilado sobre el caso de
(From Minister of Water, Lu Wenbin) flood prevention and control in the southeast.
(Del Ministro de Agua, Lu Wenbin) prevención y control de inundaciones en el sureste.
Please take a look.
Por favor, echa un vistazo.
Flood prevention and control?
¿Prevención y control de inundaciones?
It is the flood season,
Es la temporada de inundaciones,
and floods broke out frequently.
y las inundaciones estallaron con frecuencia.
(From Minister of Water, Lu Wenbin) The stricken people are suffering.
(Del Ministro de Agua, Lu Wenbin) La gente afectada está sufriendo.
However, disaster relief matters
Sin embargo, los asuntos de socorro en casos de desastre
involve a wide range of issues, and implementation is slow.
que abarquen una amplia gama de cuestiones, y la implementación es lenta.
So I think
Así que creo que
it's better to plan early.
es mejor planificar temprano.
Taking precautions
Tomar precauciones
is indeed a must.
es en efecto un deber.
Mr. Ning, you are really thoughtful.
Sr. Ning, usted es realmente considerado.
I'm flattered.
Estoy halagado.
By the way, sir.
Por cierto, señor.
I have a presumptuous request.
Tengo una petición presuntuosa.
Go ahead.
Adelante.
I have to take three days off
Tengo que tomarme tres días libres
due to my marriage.
debido a mi matrimonio.
By then, you and
Para entonces, tú y
my colleagues
mis colegas
are invited to attend.
están invitados a asistir.
Approved.
Aprobada.
Just go.
Solo ve.
Thank you, sir.
Gracias, señor.
(Self-discipline for Justice)
(Autodisciplina de la justicia)
Mr. Liu.
Sr. Liu.
The Ministry of Justice urgently reported that
El Ministerio de Justicia informó urgentemente que
a group of bandits appeared in the south of the city.
apareció un grupo de bandidos en el sur de la ciudad.
Bandits?
¿Diabetes?
Yes.
Sí.
How come?
¿Por qué?
So he is a good officer.
Así que es un buen oficial.
You have done so many evil things.
Has hecho tantas cosas malas.
Do you really think you can escape the punishment of the law?
¿Crees realmente que puedes escapar el castigo de la ley?
There are so many choices
Hay tantas opciones
in the world,
en el mundo,
but you became a bandit who brings troubles to people.
pero te volviste un bandido que trae problemas a la gente.
Now that you are a bandit,
Ahora que eres un bandido,
you should have expected today.
deberías haber esperado hoy.
It seems that my husband
Parece que mi marido
is a decisive bandit-suppressing hero.
es un héroe determinante para la represión del bandidaje.
There must be many girls
Debe haber muchas chicas
who like him.
a quien le gusta.
Right.
Bien.
Yesterday was the day
Ayer fue el día
when Marquis married
cuando Marqués se casó
his second wife.
su segunda esposa.
Second wife?
¿Segunda esposa?
He has me.
Él me tiene.
Why did he get married again?
¿Por qué se volvió a casar?
Marquis took a concubine for the first time
Marquis tomó una concubina por primera vez
after four years of marriage.
después de cuatro años de matrimonio.
You must be sad, Your Ladyship.
Debes estar triste, señora.
Listen.
Mira.
Good-looking men
Hombres de buen aspecto
are all philandering.
todos están regodeando.
Is everything arranged at home?
¿Está todo arreglado en casa?
Yes.
Sí.
(Gui Bai) The guards on patrol have doubled.
(Gui Bai) Los guardias que patrullan se han duplicado.
Our people will be placed
A nuestra gente la colocarán
among the guests.
entre los invitados.
In the process of encircling and suppressing bandits over the years,
En el proceso de cercado y reprimiendo bandidos a lo largo de los años,
there are many escaped criminals.
hay muchos criminales fugitivos.
Today is my wedding day.
Hoy es mi día de bodas.
I hope they don't miss
Espero que no se pierdan
the chance for revenge.
la posibilidad de venganza.
(Your Lordship.)
(Su Señoría.)
(Your Ladyship.)
(Su señoría.)
(Marquis doesn't allow anyone to enter.)
(Marqués no permite entrar a nadie.)
Your Ladyship, you can't get in.
Su señoría, no puedes entrar.
Your Ladyship. Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
You can't get in.
No puedes entrar.
Your Ladyship, you can't get in.
Su señoría, no puede entrar.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Marquis said you can't get in.
Marqués dijo que no puedes entrar.
Don't get in.
No te metas.
Are you really going to marry her?
¿De verdad te vas a casar con ella?
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
Is this your deployment?
¿Es este tu despliegue?
Anyone can break in.
Cualquiera puede entrar.
I disagree.
No estoy de acuerdo.
I don't allow you to marry her.
No te permito casarte con ella.
Go back to your room.
Vuelve a tu habitación.
I am the hostess of this mansion.
Soy la anfitriona de esta mansión.
I don't allow you to marry her.
No te pido matrimonio con ella.
Someone.
Alguien.
Take First Lady back to the room.
Lleva a la Primera Dama de vuelta a la habitación.
She'll be grounded today.
Hoy va a ser inmovilizada.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Ning Yuxuan!
Ning Yuxuan!
No! Ning Yuxuan!
¡No! ¡Ning Yuxuan!
Your Ladyship, let's go.
Su señoría, vamos.
Ning Yuxuan!
Ning Yuxuan!
You can't marry her.
No puedes casarte con ella.
Don't touch me!
¡No me toques!
Remember.
Recuerda.
I am the hostess of the mansion.
Soy la anfitriona de la mansión.
It seems that the relationship
Parece que la relación
between us isn't good at all,
entre nosotros no es bueno en absoluto,
is it?
es eso?
Now that he went to suppress the bandits,
Ahora que fue a suprimir a los bandidos,
who would pick up the bride?
quién recogería a la novia?
(Wen's Mansion) The bride is out.
(Mansión de Wen) La novia está fuera.
Where is Marquis?
¿Dónde está el Marqués?
Why hasn't he arrived yet?
¿Por qué aún no ha llegado?
Marquis...
Marqués...
Marquis has something important to do
Marquis tiene algo importante que hacer
and can't make it here.
y no puede hacerlo aquí.
At the order
A la orden
of the First Lady,
de la Primera Dama,
I came to pick up the Second Lady.
vine a recoger a la Segunda Dama.
You alone?
¿Estás sola?
Not me.
Yo no.
That's it.
Eso es todo.
How can you get a cock to pick up the bride?
¿Cómo puedes conseguir un galleta para recoger a la novia?
Why would I force her
¿Por qué la forzaría
to marry a cock?
casarse con un galleta?
Because you were like that
Porque eras así
back then.
entonces.
Back then...
Entonces...
I was like that?
¿Yo era así?
I held a wedding ceremony with a chicken?
Tuve una ceremonia de bodas con un pollo?
What about the wedding after that?
¿Y la boda después de eso?
Here comes the bride.
Aquí viene la novia.
It's easy to mix in today.
Es fácil mezclar hoy.
Ning's Mansion's patrol
Patrulla de Ning Mansion
shouldn't be so loose.
no debería estar tan suelta.
It's Lackey Ning's wedding day.
Es el día de la boda de Lackey Ning.
He must have been negligent.
Debe haber sido negligente.
Ask our people to be careful.
Pida a nuestra gente que tenga cuidado.
Okay.
Está bien.
Just in case.
Por si acaso.
Here comes Mr. Ning.
Aquí viene el Sr. Ning.
(Wen Wan)
(Wen Wan)
Your Lordship, here you are.
Su señoría, aquí estás.
Let's get started.
Comencemos.
Here.
Aquí.
Now is the auspicious time.
Ahora es el momento auspicioso.
Groom and bride.
Novio y novia.
The first kowtow is for heaven and earth.
El primer kowtow es para el cielo y la tierra.
Ning Yuxuan!
Ning Yuxuan!
Wait, Your Ladyship.
Espera, señora.
Here comes the First Lady.
Aquí viene la Primera Dama.
With me here,
Conmigo,
you can never marry her.
nunca podrás casarte con ella.
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
Watch your behavior.
Mira tu comportamiento.
I don't care.
No me importa.
Since we can't be a couple
Dado que no podemos ser una pareja
in this life,
en esta vida,
no one else can think about it.
nadie más puede pensarlo.
Mr. Liu.
Sr. Liu.
Go ahead.
Sigue.
Groom and bride.
Novio y novia.
The first kowtow is for heaven and earth.
El primer kowtow es para el cielo y la tierra.
Okay.
Está bien.
You forced me to do so.
Me has obligado a hacerlo.
Wen Wan!
¡Wen Wan!
Call the doctor.
Llame al médico.
Call the doctor!
¡Llama al médico!
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
It's not me!
¡Yo no soy!
Lackey Ning.
Lacayo Ning.
Go to hell!
¡Vete al infierno!
It's not me!
¡Yo no soy!
Here you are!
¡Aquí estás!
Wen Wan!
¡Wen Wan!
- Your Lordship, watch out! - Gui Bai!
- Su Señoría, ¡cuidado! Gui Bai!
Let's go!
¡Vamos!
Don't let go any of them.
No dejes ir a ninguno de ellos.
Yes!
¡Sí!
Did Miss Wen
¿La señorita Wen
just die?
acaba de morir?
No. No.
No.
Miss Wen wasn't stabbed in the vital part.
No apuñalaron a la señorita Wen en la parte vital.
She is recuperating in the mansion.
Se está recuperando en la mansión.
That's good.
Eso es bueno.
I think that
Creo que
you must have hurt your brain
debes haber dañado tu cerebro
when you fell off the cliff.
cuando se cayó del precipicio.
I'll get you the medicine.
Te conseguiré la medicina.
Maybe the memory will come back
Tal vez la memoria regrese
after you take it.
después de tomarlo.
Hold on.
Espera.
No worries about taking medicine.
No te preocupes por tomar medicinas.
My top priority now is
Mi primera prioridad ahora es
trying to escape.
tratando de escapar.
(Your Ladyship.)
(Su señoría.)
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Marquis asked you to the study.
Marquis te preguntó para el estudio.
Marquis?
¿Marqués?
I'm not going.
No voy.
Muxu.
Muxu.
You just said that
Acabas de decir que
he's No. 1 Handsome Man
es el hombre guapo nº 1
of the Capital, right?
de la Capital, ¿verdad?
Have you caught all the bandits
¿Has capturado a todos los bandidos
who assassinated at the wedding?
quién asesinó en la boda?
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
Three of them escaped.
Tres de ellos escaparon.
Check out those caught ones.
Revisa a los atrapados.
If I'm right,
Si tengo razón,
it must have something to do with the Tea Gang.
debe tener algo que hacer con la Banda de Té.
Yes.
Sí.
Marquis.
Marqués.
Here comes the First Lady.
Aquí viene la Primera Dama.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría.
Leave us alone.
Déjanos solos.
Yes.
Sí.
Honey.
Cariño.
(A gentleman should also constantly pursue progress just like nature.)
(Un señor debería también constantemente buscar el progreso igual que la naturaleza.)
♪The singing and dancing in the palace garden is over♪
♪ El canto y la danza en el jardín del palacio se acabó ♪
♪The bright moon shines on the sad wanderers♪
♪ La brillante luna brilla sobre los desagradables vagabundos ♪
♪Admiring the flowers in a lonely boat, and the flowers remain the same♪
♪ Admirando las flores en un bote solitario, y las flores siguen siendo la misma ♪
♪After a rain, the chill is gone♪
♪ Después de la lluvia, el frío se fue ♪
(His gentle appearance)
(Su suave apariencia)
(is not as sinister)
(no es tan siniestro)
(as Muxu described.)
(como describió Muxu.)
(Maybe my relationship with him)
(Tal vez mi relación con él)
(is not so bad.)
(no está tan mal.)
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
Honey.
Cariño.
I heard
He oído
there was some misunderstanding
hubo un malentendido
between us.
entre nosotros.
But I believe that
Pero creo que
it won't affect
no afectará
our relationship, right?
nuestra relación, ¿verdad?
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
Your crime of disturbing
Tu crimen de alterar
the Ning's Mansion is unforgivable.
la mansión del Ning es imperdonable.
Stop.
Detente.
I know what you're going to say.
Sé lo que vas a decir.
That's why
Por eso
I feel wronged.
me siento agraviado.
None of these things
Ninguna de estas cosas
was done by me.
lo hice yo.
Are you acting enough?
¿Estás actuando lo suficiente?
I wasn't acting.
No estaba actuando.
Do you need me
¿Me necesitas
to remind you
para recordarles
how you broke into the wedding banquet
cómo irrumpiste en el banquete de bodas
and assassinated Wen Wan?
y asesinaron a Wen Wan?
I really
Realmente
can't remember these.
no puedo recordar esto.
You are my husband.
Eres mi marido.
You have to do me justice.
Tienes que hacerme justicia.
(Don't judge anyone by appearance.)
(No juzgue a nadie por apariencia.)
(His personality is terrible.)
(Su personalidad es terrible.)
It's possible that
Es posible que
I lost my mind
perdí la mente
after falling off the cliff.
después de caerse del precipicio.
I'll go back and think about it.
Volveré a pensar en ello.
Stop!
Detente!
(Statement of Confession) Sign it.
(Declaración de confesión) Firma.
What's this?
¿Qué es esto?
Statement of Confession?
¿Declaración de confesión?
The criminal Nie Sangyu
El delincuente Nie Sangyu
did violence and abused servants.
hizo violencia y abusó de sirvientes.
Her methods are vicious and her crimes are serious.
Sus métodos son crueles y sus crímenes son graves.
She voluntarily moves to Reflection Pavilion to repent,
Se traslada voluntariamente a pabellón de reflexión para arrepentirse,
and promises to
y promete
spend the rest of her life in the Marquis's Mansion.
pasar el resto de su vida en la mansión del Marqués.
If she commits the crime again,
Si vuelve a cometer el crimen,
she will be at Ning Yuxuan's disposal.
estará a disposición de Ning Yuxuan.
(He looks so handsome.)
(Se ve tan guapo.)
(But he's so evil-minded.)
(Pero es tan malvado.)
I can't sign it.
No puedo firmarlo.
For the sake of the four years of our marriage,
Por el bien de los cuatro años de nuestro matrimonio,
you only need to sign the statement of confession,
solo necesitas firmar la confesión,
move into Reflection Pavilion,
ve al Pabellón de Reflexión,
and spend the rest of your life there
y pasa el resto de tu vida allí
from now on.
a partir de ahora.
Why should I admit to
¿Por qué debo admitir que
something I haven't done?
algo que no he hecho?
Sign the statement of confession.
Firma la confesión.
This is your only chance.
Esta es tu única oportunidad.
I won't sign it.
No lo firmaré.
Nie Sangyu.
Nie Sangyu.
Sign it or not?
Firma o no?
What are you going to do?
¿Qué vas a hacer?
I have interrogated more than a thousand prisoners.
He interrogado más de mil presos.
Tricks like faking a faint
Trucos como fingir un desmayo
are long outdated.
han quedado anticuadas.
I can't admit it.
No lo puedo admitir.
I didn't do it.
No lo hice.
Stop challenging my patience.
Deja de desafiar mi paciencia.
I will give you
Te daré
one last chance.
una última oportunidad.
Sign the statement of confession,
Firma la confesión,
and move into Reflection Pavilion.
y ve al Pabellón de Reflexión.
(Since my acting doesn't work,)
(Como mi actuación no funciona,)
(I have no choice but to...)
(No tengo más remedio que...)
I heard before that
He oído antes que
you are the Left Consul
eres el cónsul de la izquierda
who is famous all over the capital.
que es famoso en toda la capital.
Then
Entonces
if everyone knows that
si todo el mundo sabe que
you have a sinful woman as your legal wife,
tienes una mujer pecadora como tu esposa legal,
what should they think of you?
qué deben pensar de ti?
I can't do that.
No puedo hacer eso.
Everyone in the capital
Todos en la capital
knows your reputation,
conoce su reputación,
Nie Sangyu.
nie Sangyu.
I don't care anymore.
Ya no me importa.
Wait...
Espera...
I don't care if you're playing the fool
No me importa si estás jugando al tonto
or you've really lost your memory,
o has perdido realmente la memoria,
what's done is done.
lo que ha hecho está hecho.
You can't deny it.
No se puede negar.
A day together as a couple
Un día juntos como una pareja
means endless devotion.
significa devoción infinita.
- We've never spent a day together. - For the sake of...
- No hemos pasado un día juntos. - Por el bien de...
Could it be that
Podría ser que
you are still...
todavía...
You are still...
Todavía estás
Sign the statement of confession.
firma la confesión.
This is the last time I'll say it.
Esta es la última vez que lo diré.
(It seems that if I don't sign the statement of confession,)
(Parece que si no lo hago firma la confesión,)
(I can't leave here.)
(No puedo irme aquí.)
(Forget it.)
(Olvídalo.)
(Just sign it.)
(Solo firma.)
I will sign it.
Lo firmaré.
Why so angry?
¿Por qué tan enojado?
Okay, done.
Está bien, terminado.
I will move to the Reflection Pavilion.
Me trasladaré al Pabellón de Reflexión.
Nie Sangyu!
¡Nie Sangyu!
I promised to sign it.
Prometieron firmarlo.
But I didn't say what to sign.
Pero no dije qué firmar.
(Reflection Pavilion)
(Pabellón de reflexión)
After moving into the Reflection Pavilion,
Después de entrar el Pabellón de Reflexión,
we are done.
hemos terminado.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
What's this?
¿Qué es esto?
This...
Esta...
What if...
¿Y si...
What if we
Qué pasa si
can't leave here anymore?
no podemos irnos de aquí?
Marquis really asked us
Marqués realmente nos preguntó
to stay here?
para quedarnos aquí?
Now that Marquis asked us to stay here,
Ahora que el Marqués nos pidió quedarnos aquí,
let's live a good life here
vivamos una buena vida aquí
as he expected.
como él esperaba.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Didn't you use to hate
¿No lo usaban para odiar
these dirty and shabby places the most?
estos lugares sucios y basura el más?
You had to bypass these places
Tenías que evitar estos lugares
when you got out in a sedan chair.
cuando saliste en una silla de sedán.
Since
Desde
we are already here,
ya estamos aquí,
take things as they come.
toma las cosas como vienen.
Muxu.
Muxu.
Listen.
Escucha.
Put it
Ponerlo
here.
aquí.
Here.
Aquí.
Come back
Vuelve
in six hours,
en seis horas,
okay?
de acuerdo?
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Stop.
Detente.
The ground is slippery with water.
La tierra es resbaladiza con agua.
I'll be done right away.
Voy a terminar de inmediato.
No worries.
No importa.
Are you still the same person?
¿Sigues siendo la misma persona?
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
You have never done
Nunca has realizado
this kind of manual labor before.
este tipo de trabajo manual antes.
Why are you doing better than me?
¿Por qué estás mejor que yo?
If I don't hurry up,
Si no me apresuro,
where shall we live tonight?
dónde viviremos esta noche?
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Let me serve you a glass of water.
Déjame servirte un vaso de agua.
No need.
No necesito.
Put it there.
Pon ahí.
I am not thirsty.
No tengo sed.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Don't be like this.
No seas así.
I'm afraid.
Me temo.
You weren't like this before.
No eras así antes.
What's wrong, Muxu?
¿Qué pasa, Muxu?
What's going on?
¿Qué está pasando?
I may not have been like this before.
Puede que no haya sido así antes.
But
Pero
from today on,
a partir de hoy,
I am
soy
who I am now.
quién soy ahora.
It will never change.
Nunca cambiará.
But...
Pero...
I know
Ya sé
I've done a lot of things in the past
He hecho muchas cosas en el pasado
that even made myself
eso incluso me hizo
feel unbelievable.
me siento increíble.
But I promise you that
Pero te prometo que
I will never
nunca
let you live in fear
que vivas con miedo
from now on.
a partir de ahora.
Could you trust me?
¿Podría confiar en mí?
I trust you.
Confío en ti.
Your Ladyship, let's have dinner.
Su señoría, vamos a cenar.
The dinner is here?
¿La cena está aquí?
Take it out.
Quítalo.
Come on.
Vamos.
Anything delicious?
¿Algo delicioso?
Here.
Aquí.
One more.
Una más.
More?
¿Más?
Here.
Aquí.
Please eat.
Come, por favor.
That's all?
¿Eso es todo?
That's all.
Es todo.
No meat?
¿Sin carne?
Meat?
¿Carne?
You have been a vegetarian for many years
Has sido vegetariano para rezar
to pray for Marquis.
rezar por Marqués.
I have also been vegetarian
También he sido vegetariano
with you for a long time.
contigo durante mucho tiempo.
I have been vegetarian for him for many years?
He sido vegetariano para él durante muchos años?
I...
Yo...
I love him that much?
¿Le amo tanto?
Regardless of whether you are a vegetarian or not,
Independientemente de que es vegetariano o no,
Marquis specially ordered that
marqués ordenó especialmente que
those who came to Reflection Pavilion
aquellos que llegaron al Pabellón de Reflexión
can only have this kind of meal.
solo puede tener este tipo de comida.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Don't be upset.
No te molestes.
Right now,
Ahora mismo,
you'd better eat more
es mejor que comas más
and conserve your strength.
y conserve su fuerza.
Only in this way
Solo de esta manera
can we have a chance
podemos tener una oportunidad
to turn over.
para voltear.
You are right.
Tienes razón.
Beggars
Mendigos
can't be choosers.
no pueden ser selectores.
To conserve strength.
Para conservar la fuerza.
Eat!
¡Come!
I'll serve you dishes.
Te serviré platos.
Okay.
Está bien.
Here, eat more.
Aquí, come más.
It's really not like her.
En realidad no es como ella.
When you rescued her
Cuando la rescataste
back then,
en ese entonces,
were you sure it was her?
estás seguro de que era ella?
Absolutely sure.
Absolutamente seguro.
I can never
Nunca podré
mistake Her Ladyship.
confunda a Su señoría.
You mean
Quieres decir
Lady never scolded you before.
señora nunca te reprendió antes.
She had great respect for you before.
Ella tenía un gran respeto por ti antes.
But now she's so bold.
Pero ahora es tan audaz.
Look at the font.
Mira el tipo de letra.
Nie Sangyu has studied lower script since she was a child,
Nie Sangyu ha estudiado guion inferior desde que era una niña,
and her characters are delicate.
y sus personajes son delicados.
But these profound and powerful words
Pero estas palabras profundas y poderosas
cannot be written
no se puede escribir
without more than ten years of practice.
sin más de diez años de práctica.
What's
¿Qué es
Nie Sangyu up to?
nie Sangyu?
(There should be something inside.)
(Debería haber algo dentro.)
What?
¿Qué?
In the huge Ning's Mansion,
En la mansión de Ning enorme,
there is not even food in the pot.
ni siquiera hay comida en la olla.
So many goodies.
Tantos dulces.
I'm so amazing.
Soy tan increíble.
It's not burnt.
No se quema.
I can't call for help.
No puedo pedir ayuda.
Why is the fire growing stronger?
¿Por qué aumenta el fuego?
There's no need to do this for a meal.
No es necesario hacer esto para una comida.
I'd better run.
Sería mejor correr.
Who locked the door?
¿Quién cerró la puerta?
Open the door! Help!
¡Abrir la puerta! ¡Ayuda!
Fire!
Fuego!
Fire! Put out the fire!
¡Fuego! ¡Elimina el fuego!
Put out the fire!
¡Apagar el fuego!
Come on.
Vamos.
Go get more water.
Ve a buscar más agua.
I'll go get some water.
Iré a buscar algo de agua.
Come on! Water!
¡Vamos! ¡Agua!
Over there!
¡Por allá!
If I had known earlier...
Si lo hubiera sabido antes
If I had known earlier,
si lo hubiera sabido antes,
I might as well have died falling off a cliff yesterday.
podría haber muerto cayendo de un acantilado ayer.
I was about to die in a fire
Estaba a punto de morir en un incendio
just one day after coming back to life.
un día después volviendo a la vida.
Come on. Over there.
Vamos. Allá.
Okay, coming.
Está bien, viene.
Here, come on.
Aquí, vamos.
Come on.
Vamos.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
The fire is fierce here.
Aquí el fuego es feroz.
Go back first and I'll take care of it.
Vuelve primero y me encargaré de ello.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
The kitchen was on fire
La cocina estaba en llamas
when we got here.
cuando llegamos aquí.
If it goes on,
Si continúa,
the whole mansion will be burnt down.
toda la mansión será quemada.
Ask someone to tear it down.
Pida a alguien que lo rompa.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Tear it down.
Tíralo.
Okay.
Está bien.
Save me!
¡Sálvame!
Get ready to tear it down.
Prepárate para cortarlo.
Anyone there?
¿Alú ahí?
Save me!
¡Sálvame!
Someone's inside.
Hay alguien dentro.
Hurry up!
Date prisa!
Someone's there.
Alguien está allí.
Your Lordship, what are you going to do?
Su Señoría, ¿qué vas a hacer?
You have always been most afraid of fire.
Siempre has estado más miedo al fuego.
Step aside.
Aparta.
No.
No.
Your Lordship!
¡Su Señoría!
Gui Bai!
Gui Bai!
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Here.
Aquí.
Take care.
Ten cuidado.
Your Lordship, are you okay?
Su Señoría, ¿está bien?
So you were outside?
¿Así que estabas fuera?
I just yelled for a long time.
Acabo de gritar durante mucho tiempo.
I thought there was no...
Pensaba que no había...
Nie Sangyu!
¡Nie Sangyu!
You performed an assassination at the wedding last time.
Pediste un asesinato en la boda la última vez.
And you set fire this time.
Y prendiste fuego esta vez.
Do you want everyone in the mansion
¿Quieres a todos en la mansión
to die with you?
morir contigo?
I was locked inside.
Estaba encerrado dentro.
I didn't set the fire.
No incendié.
Then why are you here
Entonces, ¿por qué estás aquí
dressed like this?
vestidos así?
Your Lordship.
Su señoría.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué te pasa?
Piss off!
¡Apúrense!
You are injured.
Estás lesionado.
Take me away.
Llévame.
Yes.
Sí.
Where are you hurt?
¿Dónde estás herida?
More water.
Más agua.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
What's wrong with you?
¿Qué te pasa?
Piss off!
¡Ponte en cara!
Your Ladyship, your soothing tea.
Su señoría, su té calmante.
Muxu.
Muxu,
Do you know
¿Sabes
why Ning Yuxuan
por qué Ning Yuxuan
suddenly became like that?
de repente se volvió así?
I have no idea.
No tengo idea.
But
Pero
I think
creo que
Marquis cares about you very much.
marqués se preocupa mucho por ti.
Otherwise,
De otra manera,
he wouldn't have rushed into the fire
no hubiera corrido al fuego
to save you.
a salvarte.
It makes sense.
Tiene sentido.
He looks fierce.
Se ve feroz.
But he still has a conscience.
Pero aún tiene conciencia.
You were frightened today.
Usted estaba asustado hoy.
Go to bed earlier.
Ve a la cama antes.
I'm going to lock the door now.
Voy a bloquear la puerta ahora.
Wait.
Espera.
What's wrong, Your Ladyship?
¿Qué pasa, señora?
The kitchen door
La puerta de la cocina
was locked by someone.
fue bloqueada por alguien.
Someone wanted to kill me.
Alguien quería matarme.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría.
Your symptoms flared up again.
Sus síntomas se exacerbaron de nuevo.
How about I go get a doctor?
¿Y qué tal si voy a conseguir un médico?
No need.
No es necesario.
I know what to do.
Sé qué hacer.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
You are only curbing the disease
Solo estás reduciendo la enfermedad
by dousing yourself in ice water like this.
rociándose en agua helada como esta.
The disease cannot be eradicated.
No se puede erradicar la enfermedad.
Habit cures habit.
El hábito cura el hábito.
Get out.
Sal.
Out!
¡Fuera!
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Save me!
¡Salve a mí!
Dad!
¡Papá!
(It's been so many years.)
(Han pasado muchos años.)
(Why am I still so afraid of fire?)
(¿Por qué todavía tengo tanto miedo al fuego?)
(When exactly)
(Cuándo exactamente)
(can I overcome the demon inside?)
(puedo superar al demonio?)
Dad!
¡Papá!
Ning Yuxuan.
Ning Yuxuan.
Ning Yuxuan, it's me.
Ning Yuxuan, soy yo.
Listen.
Mira.
I think what happened in the kitchen...
Creo que lo que pasó en la cocina...
Put on your clothes.
Ponte tu ropa.
I didn't mean to
No quise
watch you take a bath.
observen que toman un baño.
I'm not interested
No me interesa
even if you're naked.
incluso si estás desnudo.
I'll count to three.
Contaré hasta tres.
Put on your clothes.
Ponte tu ropa.
One.
Una.
Two.
Dos.
I'm turning around.
Me doy la vuelta.
But you...
Pero tú...
♪Summer stars, autumn night♪
♪ estrellas de verano, noche de otoño ♪
♪Who is wandering under the moon in my heart♪
♪ Quién está vagando debajo de la luna en mi corazón ♪
♪The deepest story with the shallowest goodbye♪
♪ La historia más profunda con la más superficial adiós ♪
♪After passing by, I can only meet you in my dream♪
♪ Tras pasar, solo puedo verte en mi sueño ♪
♪The wind can't breeze the long street of time♪
♪ El viento no puede brisa la larga calle de tiempo ♪
♪The burning yearning will never cool♪
♪ El anhelo ardiente nunca se enfriará ♪
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ Dos corazones se encuentran de nuevo el amor anunciado ♪
♪How can I describe it when we look into each other's eyes♪
♪ ¿Cómo lo puedo describir cuando nos fijamos en los ojos del otro ♪
♪Take a life time to write the story♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida para escribir la historia ♪
♪Together with you♪
♪ Junto contigo ♪
♪Company you♪
♪ Compañía contigo ♪
♪Just for your glance and smile♪
♪ Solo por tu mirada y sonrisa ♪
♪The first promise means the forever love♪
♪ La primera promesa significa el amor para siempre ♪
♪Fireworks all over the sky light up your night♪
♪ fuegos artificiales por todo el cielo enciende tu noche ♪
♪Take a life time♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida ♪
♪To write the story with you gradually♪
♪ Para escribir la historia contigo gradualmente ♪
♪Just like this♪
♪ Al igual que esto ♪
♪Our love goes on and on♪
♪ Nuestro amor continúa y sigue ♪
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ El día que nos vimos por primera vez, el año en que envejecemos ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ Mi corazón y mi amor nunca desaparecerán ♪